<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Daniel Guterding</title>
    <link>https://danielguterding.github.io/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Daniel Guterding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2024 Daniel Guterding</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://danielguterding.github.io/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://danielguterding.github.io/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielguterding.github.io/home/about/</guid>
      <description>Biography I am a professor of applied mathematics at Technische Hochschule Brandenburg, located in Brandenburg an der Havel. Before joining TH Brandenburg, I lead a team of Quantitative Software Engineers at Deutsche Börse AG, one of the world&#39;s largest marketplace organizers for the trading of shares and other securities. There I worked on computational models for the pricing of financial derivatives and other software projects.
I earned my doctorate in theoretical physics on the subject of microscopic models for organic and iron-based superconductors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://danielguterding.github.io/home/publications_list/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielguterding.github.io/home/publications_list/</guid>
      <description>29. Competition of superconducting pairing symmetries in La3Ni2O7
Authors: Han-Xiang Xu, Yue Xie, Daniel Guterding, and Zhijun Wang
Preprint: arXiv
28. Near room-temperature ferromagnetism from double-exchange in van der Waals material CrGeTe3: evidence from optical conductivity under pressure
Authors: J. Ebad-Allah, D. Guterding, M. Varma, M. Diware, S. Ganorkar, H. O. Jeschke, and Ch. A. Kuntscher
Preprint: arXiv
Journal: Phys. Rev. B Letter, in press (2025)
27. Pressure tuning of intrinsic and extrinsic sources to the anomalous Hall effect in CrGeTe3</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://danielguterding.github.io/home/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielguterding.github.io/home/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Lectures at TH Brandenburg Lecture &amp;amp; Exercise course (2+2 hours/week) for each group.
Summer 2025  Probability Theory (2 groups)
 International Trade &amp;amp; Financial Markets
 Corporate Finance II
  Winter 2024/25  Mathematical Finance (2 groups)
 Corporate Finance I
 Big Data &amp;amp; Machine Learning II
  Summer 2024  Probability Theory (2 groups)
 International Trade &amp;amp; Financial Markets
 Big Data &amp;amp; Machine Learning I</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://danielguterding.github.io/home/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielguterding.github.io/home/software/</guid>
      <description>I maintain an account on Github to which I upload research codes that I deem useful for the community. These codes include:
ctaux is a continuous-time auxiliary field Monte Carlo solver for quantum impurity models. It uses a representation of the Green&#39;s function in terms of Legendre polynomials.
dhva is a code for calculating de Haas-van Alphen frequencies and electronic band masses from XCrySDen band-grid files. It works very similar to SKEAF by P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks &amp; Posters</title>
      <link>https://danielguterding.github.io/home/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielguterding.github.io/home/talks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service to the scientific community</title>
      <link>https://danielguterding.github.io/home/referee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielguterding.github.io/home/referee/</guid>
      <description>In the broader field of finance and economy I serve as a referee for various journals, including the following:
 European Journal of Operational Research Journal of Computational and Applied Mathematics  I also serve as a referee for a broad variety of scientific journals in the field of physics, which include:
 Physical Review Letters Physical Review B (Condensed Matter and Materials Physics) Nano Letters  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://danielguterding.github.io/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielguterding.github.io/home/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>